Guide to the W. J. Linton Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings by Linton, 1845–1898; Series II; 4.38; 8 boxes
  - Essays
    - "The American Odyssey: Adventures of Ulysses"; 24 p., 1876 (Box 4, Folder 161)
      With second corrected autograph manuscript written on the verso of Universal Republican Alliance subscription coupons; 35 l.
    - "Cetewayo and Dean Stanley"; 7 p., circa 1880 (Box 4, Folder 162)
      With second corrected autograph manuscript written on the verso of Universal Republican Alliance subscription coupons, 6 p.; printed in pamphlet form unsigned (Hamden: Appledore Press, 1880?).
    - "Coming Across"; 19 p., circa 1866 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - "An Essay on Thomas Paine"; 4 p., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 164)
      Addressed to the editor of Scribner's; printed in Scribner's 21, February 1881, p. 635.
    - "Fenianism and Republicanism," in The Irish Republic (May 18, 1867) (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 330)
    - "The Fight for a Free Press in England"; 20 p. and 20 p., undated (Box 4, Folder 165)
      Original rough draft written on the verso of scattered sheets of the manuscript of his Recollections, with a fair copy.
    - "A Forgotten Book"; 22 l., undated (Box 4, Folder 166)
      A paper on Essays and Sketches of Character, by the late Richard Ayton (London: Taylor and Hessey, 1825).
    - "Ireland's Remedy, by an Englishman"; 12 p., undated (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - "James Watson"; 105 p., undated (Box 4, Folder 168)
      On his friend, the London publisher; written on the verso of Universal Republican Alliance subscription coupons.
    - "Joseph Mazzini," in The Avenue 1, vo. 2 (November 1896), 1896 November (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - "Lamennais"; 14 p., undated (Box 4, Folder 170)
      Written on the verso of scattered proof sheets of his Reminiscences which he had used for compiling the index.
    - On Thomas Sibson; 19 p., 1845 (Box 4, Folder 171)
      A eulogy for Sibson (1817-1844), a fellow artist, "Read at the Institute of Fine Arts in the beginning of 1845."
    - "The Paris Commune," in The Radical 9, no. 2 (September 1871), 1871 September (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - "The Religion of Organization," in The Radical 5, no. 4 (April 1869), 1869 April (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - "Reminiscences of Eben Jones"; 23 p., 1897 March (Box 4, Folder 174)
      Regarding the Chartist poet Ebenezer Jones (1820-1860); published in Studies of Sensation and Event: Poems by Ebenezer Jones (London: Pickering and Company, 1879).
    - "Who were the Chartists?," in Century Magazine 23 (January 1882), 1882 January (Box 4, Folder 175)
      One line corrected at end.
    - Clippings from journals and newspapers, 1848–1866 (Box 4, Folder 176)
      Contains clippings and tear sheets, most from unidentified sources.
  - Lectures
    - "Wood Engraving in the 15th and 16th Centuries"; 40 p., 1886 (Box 4, Folder 177)
      Lecture delivered at the Grolier Club on November 8, 1886, and at the Century Club on December 8, 1886. With two printed tickets for the Grolier Club event.
    - "Engraving in Wood"; 40 and 34 p., 1889 February (Box 4, Folder 178)
      Two lectures delivered as the Cantor Lectures at the Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures and Commerce, Adelphi, London, on February 11 and 18, 1889. Accompanied by manuscript syllabus for the two lectures (1 p.) and printed invitation/syllabus (1 p.)
    - "Engraving in Wood," illustrated précis of lectures, in Journal of the Society of Arts 37, no. 1911 (July 5, 1889), 1889 July 5 (Box 4, Folder 179)
      Two copies.
    - "Engraving in Wood: Old and New, concerning the use of lines in engraving"; 25 p., 1890 March 25 (Box 4, Folder 180)
      Lecture delivered at the Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures and Commerce, Adelphi, London, on March 25, 1890. Accompanied by printed postal announcement of lecture (1 p.)
    - "Engraving in Wood: Old and New" in Journal of the Society of Arts 38, no. 1950 (April 4, 1890), 1890 April 4 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - On John Greenleaf Whittier; 37 p., 1893 March (Box 4, Folder 182)
      Lecture delivered at the Century Club, March 1893.
  - Poems
    The subseries contains original poems by Linton, and copies by him of poems by others.
    - "Against Landlordism"; 36 l., undated (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - "All Right Behind"; 1 p., circa 1885 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - "Attraction"; 1 p., undated (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - "Born Lucky" (Moritz Schiller); 13 p., undated (Box 5, Folder 186)
      Laid in: "Two Brothers"; 9 p.
    - "Broadway Ballads"; 151 l., 1875 (Box 5, Folder 187)
      "Fairly copied December 17, 1875." Written on the verso of Universal Republican Alliance subscription coupons; with separate table of contents.
    - "Catoninetales and Other Poems. By Hattie Brown. Second edition"; 164 p., 44 p., undated (Box 5, Folder 188)
      Composed partly of printed clippings mounted and partly written in duplicate. Various pagings; mostly written the verso of Universal Republican Alliance subscription coupons.
    - "Children's Songs"; copy of songs suitable for children; 24 p., undated (Box 5, Folder 189)
      With 10 printed clippings.
    - "Children's Songs"; with graphite and wash drawings, 16 p., undated (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - "Chansons"; 80 p., undated (Box 5, Folder 191)
      A collection of French songs done into English in the original forms, arranged for printing, with preface, contents, notes, and title page.
    - "Coupling"; 1 p., undated (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - "England to America, 1876. A New Year's Greeting"; 6 p. (Box 5, Folder 193)
      Autograph manuscript with head and tail pieces mounted; accompanied by printed version with uncut title page (Cambridge: Welch, Bigelow & Co., University Press, 1876?), 8 p.
    - "English Heroes"; incomplete, circa 55 p., 1853 (Box 5, Folder 194)
      Bound in white boards; originally titled "English Champions."
    - "Epithalamium"; 4 p., undated (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - "Five Sermons from One Text", undated (Box 5, Folder 196)
      Bound volume with poems written and pasted in, including some clipped from unidentified printed sources. Accompanied by loose sheets of poems dated 1864-1896 and including "Two Million Men," a sketch of a title page for "Hesperus," a draft if :Kitten's Growlings by a Little Girl," and a wood engraved portrait of an unidentified man.
      Gift of Mansfield Merriman, 1964.
    - "The Flood of Years, after Bryant"; 12 p., 1877 August 29 (Box 5, Folder 197)
      "The artist's interpretation of the same, First draught, written in three hours, pencil corrections afterwards." Accompanied by a second autograph draft (14 p.), and graphite drawings designed for the illustrated edition to be published by G. Putnam's Sons (24 p.)
    - "Forget-me-not" (Hamden: Appledore Private Press), 1896 December (Box 5, Folder 198)
      Folder with a poem and a colored illustration; with envelope postmarked 1896 and addressed to Ellen Linton, care of Mrs. Foote, North Star Mines, Grass Valley, California.
    - "Golden Apples of Hesperus"; 214 p., 1881 (Box 5, Folder 199)
      Manuscript set up as printer's dummy indicating the placement of engravings by Linton to illustrate the volume. The preface, captions, contents, and notes written in ink and pencil, with the illustrations shown by sketches in pencil or mounted prints; laid between original boards. Accompanied by one of the first impressions of the engraved title page of the 1882 edition (Hamden: Appledore Private Press, 1882).
    - "Grenville's Last Fight," in The Newcastle Weekly Chronicle (August 11, 1888), 1888 August 11 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 331)
    - "Heroic Verse"; 63 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 200)
      Copies of verses from selected authors.
    - "Hullaloo"; 5 p., 1875 February 17 (Box 6, Folder 201)
      With note at the end: "Impromptu Feb 17, 1875 first draft." Printed in revised form as pages 13-15 of his Pot-Pourri (New York: S. W. Green, 1875).
    - "I Could Go On, Do I Not Hear"; 2 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - "If"; 1 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - "Is it True?"; 1 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - "King Cophetua"; 1 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 205)
      See pages 35-36 of his Heliconundrums (Hamden: Appledore Press, 1892).
    - "Lizzie's Posy"; 36 l., 1856 July 1 (Box 6, Folder 206)
      Drawings in graphite and watercolor of wildflowers around Brantwood, with autograph descriptions in rhyme, dedicated to "Baby Lizzie" (Elizabeth Lynn Linton) on her second birthday.
    - "Love-Lore"; printed specimen sheets, 10 l., circa 1895 (Box 6, Folder 207)
      Printed with blank versos, numbered pages 247-248 (2 copies) and 253-254 (3 copies); published as pages 227-228 and 241-242 of his Love-lore and Other Early and Late Poems (Hamden: Appledore Press, 1895).
    - "Maud Muller again (Whittier)"; 4 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 208)
      Written on the verso of Universal Republican Alliance subscription coupons.
    - "Merry Hannah (Tennyson); 4 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 209)
    - "Mrs. Caudle in her cups: a domestic idyll"; 3 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 210)
    - "On a Certain Fashion"; autograph poem, 1 p., 1883 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - "One corner of my garden is overgrown…"; 1 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - "A Pagan Outlook"; 4 p., 1896 February 18 (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - "The Parrot (Poe)"; 8 p., undated (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - "Poems, 1865-6", 1865–1866 (Box 6, Folder 215)
      Bound in white boards.
    - The Poor-house Fugitive Being the Life and Adventure of Bob Thin (Hamden: Appledore Press, 1897): unbound signatures (Box 6, Folder 216-219)
      Two sets.
    - "Pot-pourri"; 24 p., 1875 (Box 7, Folder 220)
    - "So Miller's Died (After Miller) Old Revels"; 4 p., undated (Box 7, Folder 221)
      Related to "Kit Carson's Ride" by Joachim Miller.
    - "Some Songs"; 25 p., 1877 September (Box 7, Folder 222)
    - "Songs and Hymns and Objurgations by Spartacus"; 285 p., 1895 (Box 7, Folder 223-224)
      "Corrected and in order for the printer"; title page has mounted engraving, tinted; with a piece of the original wrapper.
    - "Sonnet"; 1 p., undated (Box 7, Folder 225)
    - "The Teuton to the Cabbage (Bayard Taylor Translated to Leland)"; 2 p., undated (Box 7, Folder 226)
    - "Theft" and "Criticism"; 1 p., 1877 February 2 (Box 7, Folder 227)
      Written on the verso of his subscription form for Engraving on Wood (1867).
    - "Tom King's Wake: a Surprize Party"; 34 l., 1876 September 15 (Box 7, Folder 228)
    - "Transatlantic Verse: A Sheaf of Songs from the Less Known Singers of the Present Century"; 125 l., undated (Box 7, Folder 229)
    - "When the Soul is Heavy with Sadness"; 1 p., undated (Box 7, Folder 230)
    - Wild Flowers for Children. Part 1, by Mr. Honeysuckle (London: C. Honeysuckle, ca. 1857): printed wrappers (Box 7, Folder 231)
      Some with added watercolor.
    - Wind-falls: Two Hundred and Odd (Hamden: Appledore Private Press, 1879), circa 1875
      - Autograph manuscript; 92 p., circa 1879 (Box 7, Folder 232)
      - Proof sheets with autograph corrections, circa 1879 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 332)
    - "The Wisdom of Aesop"; 25 p., circa 1880 (Box 7, Folder 233)
    - "Written between 42 and 49 but not printed", undated (Box 7, Folder 234)
      Part of a collection: pages numbered 81 to 99.
    - Printed poems: proofs and clipped from serials and pages from books, 1855–1897 (Box 7, Folder 235)
  - Prospectuses
    - The Cause of the People, 1848 (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - Claribel and Other Poems, circa 1856 (Box 7, Folder 237)
    - English Republic, 1853 (Box 7, Folder 238)
    - English Verse, circa 1883 (Box 7, Folder 239)
    - Engraving on Wood, 1867 (Box 7, Folder 240)
    - Golden Apples of Hesperus, circa 1882 (Box 7, Folder 241)
      Removed from Linton's Golden Apples of Hesperus (BEIN 2005 1169).
    - The Leader, 1850 (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - Love-Lore, circa 1887 (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - Masters of Wood Engraving, circa 1886 (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - Pen and Pencil, 1855 (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - Poems and Translations, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 246)
  - Other Writings
    - Scrapbook of writings by Linton, 1865–1881 (Box 7, Folder 247)
      Poems, published essays, and letters to editors clipped from serials; a gift from Ellen Linton to William and Ada Hopson.
    - "The Army Worm," in the New Haven Union, circa 1882 (Box 8, Folder 248)
      Letter to the editor.
    - "Biblia in King's College Library"; 6 p., undated (Box 8, Folder 249)
      Autograph checklist of religious books.
    - "Early Wood-cuts: the Helgen and Block-books"; 12 p., 1894 April (Box 8, Folder 250)
      With two mounted prints. Related to Linton's Cantor lectures; see Journal of the Society of Arts 37, no. 1911 (July 5, 1889): 676-682.
    - The English Lakes (London: Hamilton, Adams Co., ca. 1865), circa 1865 (Box 8, Folder 251)
      Proof pages, corrected.
    - The English Republic: a Series of Tracts (London: J. Watson, 1852-1853); vol. 2: cut page sheets (Box 8, Folder 252)
      Pages 9-396 (only); possibly for use as proof sheets.
    - The Flower and the Star and Other Stories for Children (Boston: Ticknor and Fields, 1868)
      - "The Flower and the Star and other Stories for Children: Kitten's Growlings"; 91 p., undated (Box 8, Folder 253)
        "The Flower and the Star" begins on page 64.
      - "Another Jack the Giant Killer," in Pen and Pencil (March 24, 1855), 1855 March 24 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 333)
      - "The Flower and the Star or the Course of the Stream"; 59 p., circa 1868 (Box 8, Folder 254)
        Accompanied by page proofs (29 p.); manuscript contains rough pulls of cuts by Linton which do not appear in the printed work. Published with title: The Flower and the Star and Other Stories for Children.
        Purchased from Seven Gables Bookshop on the Library Associates Fund, 1952.
      - India proof pages, 1868 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 334)
      - Printed signatures, unbound, 1868 (Box 8, Folder 255)
    - A Good Child's Alphabet; printed pages with autograph cover, circa 1860 (Box 8, Folder 256)
      Original sketches/dummy for publication is at John Hay Library, Brown University Library (76 L761gc).
    - "The Humorists in Verse (English-Scottish-Irish) of the Nineteenth Century"; 242 l., undated (Box 9, Folder 257-258)
    - The Lake Country, by E. Lynn Linton, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 259)
      Illustrations by Linton; proof sheets, corrected.
    - "Life of John Greenleaf Whittier"; 249 p., circa 1892 (Box 9, Folder 260-261)
      Published as Life of John Greenleaf Whittier (London: W. Scott, Ltd., 1893).
    - "Specimens of a new process of engraving for surface-printing" (Box 9, Folder 262)
      Scrapbook with title pages and four text pages from Linton's book on cerography (London: W.J. Linton, 1861)
      Gift of Alfred E. Hamill (Yale 1905), 1928.
    - "Some Practical Hints on Wood-engraving"; 202 p., 1879 (Box 9, Folder 263)
      Prepared for the published edition (Boston: Lee and Shepard; New York: Charles T. Dillingham, 1879). Accompanied by printed advertisement for the publication, titled: "The Critics Criticised," distributed by Lee and Shepard (1 p.)
    - "Wood-engraving in America"; 151 p., circa 1879 (Box 9, Folder 264)
      Prepared for publication as The History of Wood-engraving in America (Boston: Estes and Lauriat, 1882); inscribed in upper right: "(Lent to Univ. Press, Jan. 26/80)."
    - Writings in the National Anti-Slavery Standard, 1868 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 335)
      Full issues of vol. 29, nos. 1, 8, and 21 (May 9, June 27, September 26)
    - Writings in the National Standard, 1870–1872 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 336)
    - Unidentified writings
      - "There Were Three Brothers—Cain, Abel, and One Yet Unnamed"; 1 p., undated (Box 9, Folder 265)
        Page 19 of a manuscript; written on the verso of a printed form letter from the Democratic Committee of Observation on the French Revolution, dated March 15, 1848.
      - Introduction to a biographical work; 8 p., undated (Box 9, Folder 266)
        Purchased from the Brick Row Book Shop on the William Robertson Coe American Studies Fund, 1966.
      - Manuscript with verses, essays, and Bible citations, undated (Box 9, Folder 267)
      - Manuscript about excursions from Keswick, 1868 April 7 (Box 9, Folder 268)
        Page 8 of a manuscript; written on the verso of a meeting notice from American Society of Painters in Watercolor dated April 1, 1868.
- Writings about Linton, 1839–1937; Series III; 1.71
  The series holds writings about Linton published during his lifetime and after his death. See also the bound volume owned by Ellen Linton in Box 3, folder 160, which includes writings by and about Linton.
  Series III is organized into two subseries: Book and Exhibition Reviews, and Profiles, Obituaries, and Other Tributes.
  - Book and Exhibition Reviews
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - Review of The National and a "Sonnet to W. J. Linton," in The Odd Fellow 1, no. 47 (November 23, 1839), 1839 November 23 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 337)
    - Bob Thin, or the Poor House Fugitive, 1846–1849 (Box 15, Folder 339)
    - The Plaint of Freedom, 1853 (Box 15, Folder 340)
    - The Lake Country, 1864 (Box 15, Folder 341)
    - Masters of Wood Engraving, 1888–1892 (Box 10, Folder 269)
    - Masters of Wood Engraving, 1889–1891 (Box 15, Folder 342)
    - "A Note on 'The Masters of Wood Engraving,' by W. J. Linton," by Arthur H. Mackmurdo, in The Century Guild Hobby Horse 28 (October 1892), 1892 October (Box 15, Folder 343)
    - Other book reviews, 1854–1931 (Box 10, Folder 270)
    - Other book reviews, 1851–1893 (Box 15, Folder 344)
    - Reviews of public exhibitions of Linton's graphic works, 1883–1898 (Box 14 (Oversize), Folder 338)
  - Profiles, Obituaries, and Other Tributes
    - "W. J. Linton, the Celebrated Engraver," in Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper 23, no. 593 (February 9, 1867), 1867 February 9 (Box 16, Folder 345)
      Linton's first issue, with a cover illustration by him and a biographical sketch (with self-portrait) inside.
    - "William James Linton," in the Civil Service Review (March 18, 1876), 1876 March 18 (Box 16, Folder 346)
    - "The Appledore Private Press, U.S.A.," by A. H. Bullen, in The Library 1 (1889) (Box 10, Folder 271)
    - "William James Linton, engraver, poet, and political writer," by Frederic G. Kitton, in English Illustrated Magazine 8, no. 91 (April 1891), 1891 April (Box 10, Folder 272)
      Includes portrait engraved by W. Biscombe Gardner.
    - "Three Veterans of Wood-Engraving," by M. H. Spielmann, in The Illustrated London News (May 14, 1892), 1892 May 14 (Box 16, Folder 347)
    - "William James Linton. Artist, Poet, and Politician," by F. Stroud, in The Cheltenham Examiner (December 28, 1892), 1892 December 28 (Box 16, Folder 348)
    - "With William James Linton," in the New York Times (October 29, 1893), 1893 October 29 (Box 10, Folder 273)
    - "W J Linton's Publications", 1897 May 9 (Box 10, Folder 274)
      Manuscript list in unidentified hand.
    - "To W. J. Linton," by George Markham Tweddell, in the Newcastle Weekly Chronicle (November 4, 1897), 1897 November 4 (Box 10, Folder 275)
    - Obituary in The Athenaeum, no. 3663 (January 1898), 1898 January (Box 10, Folder 276)
    - Obituaries, 1898 (Box 16, Folder 349)
    - "William J. Linton," by Caroline A. Powell, in The Art Interchange 40, no. 3 (March 1898), 1898 March (Box 16, Folder 350)
    - "The Wood-Engravings of William James Linton," by Kineton Parkes, in The Bookman's Journal Print Collector 4, nos. 89-90 (July 1921), 1921 July (Box 10, Folder 277)
    - "The Appledore Private Press," by Kineton Parkes, in The Bookman's Journal Print Collector 4, no. 94 (August 12 1921), 1921 August 21 (Box 10, Folder 278)
    - "Belated Reverence Paid to Linton, Poet-Printer," in New Haven Register (July 1, 1931), 1931 July 1 (Box 16, Folder 351)
      Subtitled: "Elm City Residents of His Day Failed to Realize How Great He Was"
    - "Side Lights on William James Linton, 1812-1897," by William Fowler Hopson; typescript, corrected, circa 1933 (Box 10, Folder 279)
      Published in The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America 27, no. 2 (1933).
    - "Letters of Mazzini to W. J. Linton," by Frederick W. Hoeing (in Journal of Modern History 5, no. 2 (March 1933), 1933 March (Box 10, Folder 280)
    - "Old Hand Press Recalls Life of William Linton," by Charlotte B. Sills in the New Haven Register (October 6, 1937), 1937 October 6 (Box 10, Folder 281)
    - "To thee O Linton I resign my crown…", undated (Box 10, Folder 282)
      Manuscript poem signed and illustrated by J. F. or F. J. (monogram)
    - Other writings about Linton, 1850–1920 (Box 10, Folder 283)
      Clippings from newspapers and serials; the 1900 article is titled "Linton at Brantwood."
    - Other writings about Linton, 1879–1891 (Box 16, Folder 352)
- Graphic Material, 1838–1913; Series IV; 7.22; 6 boxes
  Series IV is organized into four subseries: Drawings and Paintings, Prints, Serials, and Sketchbooks.
  The series holds graphic work created by Linton in several media, including three small oil portraits of family members. Important here are albums of his engraved work from the early 1840s, 1850s, and 1860s, including an album compiled by Lancelot Wade Linton (ca. 1846-1863), one of Linton's three sons. Also present are four of his English sketchbooks with graphite and watercolor views of the Lake District.
  - Drawings and Paintings
    - Personal work
      - "Appledore", 1885–1890 (Box 10, Folder 284)
        Four drawings in graphite and watercolor on paper: apple tree, house exterior, study, and press room; the latter drawing inscribed: "Original drawing done for S. P. Avery."
      - "Looking down the Lake, near Low Wood, Windermere"; graphite on paper mounted on card, undated (Box 10, Folder 285)
      - Portrait of Laura Carthew Wade; oil on card, undated (Box 16, Folder 353)
      - Portrait of Laura Wade Linton (1809-1838); oil on board, circa 1838 (Box 10, Folder 286)
      - Portrait of a young girl; oil on board, circa 1845 (Box 10, Folder 287)
      - Sketch of "Bramble," Linton's coat of arms, and unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 288)
    - Work for Publication
      - "Fairy-tales"; seventeen wash sketches on paper, undated (Box 10, Folder 289)
      - "The Farthing Times," no. 1, 1862 (Box 16, Folder 354)
        Paste-up with manuscript captions, composed of printed clippings and illustrations from other journals.
      - "The Illustrated Magazine," no. 1, 1863 (Box 10, Folder 290)
      - "The Men in the Moon"; 4 l. of sketches; graphite and wash on paper, undated (Box 10, Folder 291)
      - "Thanatopsis"; nine graphite sketches on paper, circa 1876 (Box 10, Folder 292)
        Sketches for title page and illustrations for William Cullen Bryant's Thanatopsis (New York: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1877).
        Removed from Bryant's The Flood of Years, with thirteen designs by W. J. Linton (New York: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1877).
      - "Thirty Odd Cuts at Old Time: being a new version of the History of England by Bob Thin"; 4 p., undated (Box 10, Folder 293)
        Paste-up with manuscript captions and three wood engravings.
      - Sketches for prospective journals, undated (Box 17, Folder 356)
      - "Hymns and Music"; proof sheets, corrected, undated (Box 16, Folder 355)
        Verses by Sarah Flower Adams, music by Eliza Flower, and floral decorations by Linton.
      - Other sketches, undated (Box 10, Folder 294)
        Includes a layout for program for "Lord Bateman," a masthead for "The Red Republican," and a small booklet titled "Spring Flowers," with two printed advertisements for C. Honeysuckle's children's books on flowers, fruits, and leaves.
  - Prints